<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bert on R&#39;nalytics</title>
    <link>/categories/bert/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bert on R&#39;nalytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cmn-Hant</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/bert/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is XLNet and Why It Outperforms BERT  </title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-xlnet-and-why-it-outperforms-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-is-xlnet-and-why-it-outperforms-bert/</guid>
      <description>What Is XLNet and Why It Outperforms BERT [ read more ] Basic knowledge of XLNet to understand the difference between XLNet and BERT intuitively 4 min read
 Building a Simple Chatbot from Scratch in Python (using NLTK) [ read more ] Gartner estimates that by 2020, chatbots will be handling 85 percent of customer-service interactions; they… 11 min read
 Adapters: A Compact and Extensible Transfer Learning Method for NLP [ read more ] Adapters obtain comparable results to BERT on several NLP tasks while achieving parameter efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19 Things You Need to Learn to Become an Effective Angular Developer  </title>
      <link>/posts/19-things-you-need-to-learn-to-become-an-effective-angular-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/19-things-you-need-to-learn-to-become-an-effective-angular-developer/</guid>
      <description>19 Things You Need to Learn to Become an Effective Angular Developer [ read more ] A comprehensive guide on how to become a pro at Angular 10 min read
 An introduction to Git merge and rebase: what they are, and how to use them [ read more ] As a Developer, many of us have to choose between Merge &amp;amp; Rebase. With all the references we get from the… 6 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic NLP Tutorial for News Multiclass Categorization  </title>
      <link>/posts/a-basic-nlp-tutorial-for-news-multiclass-categorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-basic-nlp-tutorial-for-news-multiclass-categorization/</guid>
      <description>A Basic NLP Tutorial for News Multiclass Categorization [ read more ] Natural Language Processing, Support Vector Machine, TF- IDF, deep learning, Spacy, Attention LSTM 6 min read
 Dissecting BERT Part 1: The Encoder [ read more ] This is Part 1/2 of Understanding BERT written jointly by Miguel Romero and Francisco Ingham. If you already… 12 min read
 Machine Learning is Fun! [ read more ] The world’s easiest introduction to Machine Learning 15 min read</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>