<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on R&#39;nalytics</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on R&#39;nalytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cmn-Hant</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Make your JavaScript elegant with recursions  </title>
      <link>/posts/make-your-javascript-elegant-with-recursions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/make-your-javascript-elegant-with-recursions/</guid>
      <description>Make your JavaScript elegant with recursions [ read more ] A short guide 6 min read
 Examining Gender and Race Bias in Sentiment Analysis Systems [ read more ] The study determines whether sentiment analysis systems display inappropriate human biases. 6 min read
 The Easy Guide to Python Command Line Arguments 😎 [ read more ] One of the strengths of Python is that it comes with the ability to do just about anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write to Express, Not to Impress  </title>
      <link>/posts/write-to-express-not-to-impress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/write-to-express-not-to-impress/</guid>
      <description>Write to Express, Not to Impress [ read more ] 18 quick fixes to sharpen your writing 6 min read
 Animations with Matplotlib [ read more ] Animations are an interesting way of demonstrating a phenomenon. We as humans are always enthralled by… 6 min read
 I created the exact same app in React and Vue. Here are the differences. [2019… [ read more ] React vs Vue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Value-based drafting for Wide Receiver in Standard and PPR in the 2019 Fantasy…  </title>
      <link>/posts/value-based-drafting-for-wide-receiver-in-standard-and-ppr-in-the-2019-fantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/value-based-drafting-for-wide-receiver-in-standard-and-ppr-in-the-2019-fantasy/</guid>
      <description>Value-based drafting for Wide Receiver in Standard and PPR in the 2019 Fantasy… [ read more ] According to our machine learning models and the Fantasy Outliers team, these Wide Receivers could return… 5 min read
 How does Ethereum work, anyway? [ read more ] Introduction 33 min read
 Helm 3: Fun With the New Beta [ read more ] Cleaner, simpler and more secure, with the previous functions you love 4 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PyTorch 1.2 Quickstart with Google Colab  </title>
      <link>/posts/pytorch-1.2-quickstart-with-google-colab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pytorch-1.2-quickstart-with-google-colab/</guid>
      <description>PyTorch 1.2 Quickstart with Google Colab [ read more ] In this tutorial, we will learn how to quickly train a deep learning model to understand some of PyTorch’s… 6 min read
 Beyond Word Embeddings Part 2- Word Vectors &amp;amp; NLP Modeling from BoW to BERT [ read more ] A primer in the neural nlp model archticture and word representation. 10 min read
 🚀 100 Times Faster Natural Language Processing in Python [ read more ] How to take advantage of spaCy &amp;amp; a bit of Cython for blazing fast NLP 10 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strings, Unicode, and Bytes in Python 3: Everything You Always Wanted to Know  </title>
      <link>/posts/strings-unicode-and-bytes-in-python-3-everything-you-always-wanted-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/strings-unicode-and-bytes-in-python-3-everything-you-always-wanted-to-know/</guid>
      <description>Strings, Unicode, and Bytes in Python 3: Everything You Always Wanted to Know [ read more ] Understanding the significant new features of Python 3 9 min read
 Data Visualization with Bokeh in Python, Part III: Making a Complete Dashboard [ read more ] Creating an interactive visualization application in Bokeh 10 min read
 Designing Well-Structured REST APIs with Flask-RestPlus: Part 1 [ read more ] This is the first part of a two-part series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) in Keras  </title>
      <link>/posts/building-a-convolutional-neural-network-cnn-in-keras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/building-a-convolutional-neural-network-cnn-in-keras/</guid>
      <description>Building a Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) in Keras [ read more ] Deep Learning is becoming a very popular subset of machine learning due to its high level of performance… 7 min read
 Deep learning for recommender systems [ read more ] How we improve vehicle recommendations at mobile.de 12 min read
 Recommendation System Algorithms [ read more ] Main existing recommendation engines and how they work 6 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors?  </title>
      <link>/posts/what-are-eigenvalues-and-eigenvectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-are-eigenvalues-and-eigenvectors/</guid>
      <description>What are Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors? [ read more ] A must-know concept for Machine Learning 9 min read
 Why Data Normalization is necessary for Machine Learning models [ read more ] Normalization is a technique often applied as part of data preparation for machine learning. The goal of… 4 min read
 Remember the $86 million license plate scanner I replicated? I caught someone… [ read more ] A few weeks ago, I published what I thought at the time was a fairly innocuous article: How I replicated an… 11 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Model Trees from scratch  </title>
      <link>/posts/introduction-to-model-trees-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/introduction-to-model-trees-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Model Trees from scratch [ read more ] A Decision Tree is a powerful supervised learning tool in Machine Learning for splitting up your data into… 4 min read
 RL - Model-based Reinforcement Learning [ read more ] In reinforcement learning RL, we maximize the rewards for our actions. By simply looking at the equation… 12 min read
 A brief introduction to reinforcement learning [ read more ] Reinforcement Learning is an aspect of Machine learning where an agent learns to behave in an environment, by… 10 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying KL Divergence  </title>
      <link>/posts/demystifying-kl-divergence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/demystifying-kl-divergence/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying KL Divergence [ read more ] What does KL stand for? Is it a distance measure? What does it mean to measure the similarity of two… 6 min read
 Bayesian Neural Network Series Post 1: Need for Bayesian Networks [ read more ] This post is the first post in an eight-post series of Bayesian Convolutional Networks. The posts will be… 6 min read
 A Simple Neural Network from Scratch with PyTorch and Google Colab [ read more ] In this tutorial we will implement a simple neural network from scratch using PyTorch and Google Colab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why and How To Use Docker for Development  </title>
      <link>/posts/why-and-how-to-use-docker-for-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-and-how-to-use-docker-for-development/</guid>
      <description>Why and How To Use Docker for Development [ read more ] Docker is not just for deployment, it’s great for development too 5 min read
 Deep Reinforcement Learning with TensorFlow 2.0 [ read more ] In this tutorial I will showcase the upcoming TensorFlow 2.0 features through the lense of deep reinforcement… 10 min read
 FastText sentiment analysis for tweets: A straightforward guide. [ read more ] The essential about fastText architecture, cleaning, upsampling and tweets classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure Your iPhone to Work for You, Not Against You  </title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-configure-your-iphone-to-work-for-you-not-against-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-configure-your-iphone-to-work-for-you-not-against-you/</guid>
      <description>How to Configure Your iPhone to Work for You, Not Against You [ read more ] The very, very complete guide to productivity, focus, and your own longevity 75 min read
 WTF is The Blockchain? [ read more ] The ultimate 3500-word guide in plain English to understand Blockchain. 16 min read
 Simplify your JavaScript – Use .map(), .reduce(), and .filter() [ read more ] If you haven’t heard of .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Center Things With Style in CSS  </title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-center-things-with-style-in-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-center-things-with-style-in-css/</guid>
      <description>How to Center Things With Style in CSS [ read more ] We’ve all found ourselves frustrated with centering things in CSS 5 min read
 Introducing npx: an npm package runner [ read more ] [You can also read this post in Russian.] 7 min read
 JSON - The Python Way [ read more ] What is JSON ? - The Fat-Free Alternative to XML. 7 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to Natural Language Generation  </title>
      <link>/posts/a-comprehensive-guide-to-natural-language-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-comprehensive-guide-to-natural-language-generation/</guid>
      <description>A Comprehensive Guide to Natural Language Generation [ read more ] As long as Artificial Intelligence helps us to get more out of the natural language, we see more tasks and… 9 min read
 The 2018 DevOps RoadMap [ read more ] An illustrated guide to becoming a Frontend or Backend Developer with links to courses 10 min read
 face-api.js - JavaScript API for Face Recognition in the Browser with… [ read more ] A JavaScript API for Face Detection, Face Recognition and Face Landmark Detection 9 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adapters: A Compact and Extensible Transfer Learning Method for NLP  </title>
      <link>/posts/adapters-a-compact-and-extensible-transfer-learning-method-for-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adapters-a-compact-and-extensible-transfer-learning-method-for-nlp/</guid>
      <description>Adapters: A Compact and Extensible Transfer Learning Method for NLP [ read more ] Adapters obtain comparable results to BERT on several NLP tasks while achieving parameter efficiency. 5 min read
 Multi-Class Text Classification with Scikit-Learn [ read more ] There are lots of applications of text classification in the commercial world. For example, news stories are… 11 min read
 Building a Simple Chatbot from Scratch in Python (using NLTK) [ read more ] Gartner estimates that by 2020, chatbots will be handling 85 percent of customer-service interactions; they… 11 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Label Text Classification with Scikit-Learn  </title>
      <link>/posts/multi-label-text-classification-with-scikit-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/multi-label-text-classification-with-scikit-learn/</guid>
      <description>Multi Label Text Classification with Scikit-Learn [ read more ] Multi-class classification means a classification task with more than two classes; each label are mutually… 6 min read
 Fully Utilizing Your Deep Learning GPUs [ read more ] There are a lot of articles having to do with deep learning and deep learning frameworks, and there is a lot… 16 min read
 50+ Data Structure and Algorithms Interview Questions for Programmers [ read more ] There are a lot of computer science graduates and programmers applying for programming, coding, and software… 11 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Marks of a True Senior Developer  </title>
      <link>/posts/the-marks-of-a-true-senior-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-marks-of-a-true-senior-developer/</guid>
      <description>The Marks of a True Senior Developer [ read more ] And how to spot them in the wild 5 min read
 No, Machine Learning is not just glorified Statistics [ read more ] This meme has been all over social media lately, producing appreciative chuckles across the internet as the… 10 min read
 Why Don’t “Good Men” Believe Women? [ read more ] MeToo’s next step isn’t about Bad Men, but about masculinity 9 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Classification with State of the Art NLP Library  -  Flair  </title>
      <link>/posts/text-classification-with-state-of-the-art-nlp-library-flair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/text-classification-with-state-of-the-art-nlp-library-flair/</guid>
      <description>Text Classification with State of the Art NLP Library - Flair [ read more ] Exciting news! A new version of Flair - state-of-the-art NLP library has just been released. Learn how to use… 6 min read
 Machine Learning with Python: NLP and Text Recognition [ read more ] In this article I apply a series of natural language processing techniques on a dataset containing reviews… 6 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is XLNet and Why It Outperforms BERT  </title>
      <link>/posts/what-is-xlnet-and-why-it-outperforms-bert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/what-is-xlnet-and-why-it-outperforms-bert/</guid>
      <description>What Is XLNet and Why It Outperforms BERT [ read more ] Basic knowledge of XLNet to understand the difference between XLNet and BERT intuitively 4 min read
 Building a Simple Chatbot from Scratch in Python (using NLTK) [ read more ] Gartner estimates that by 2020, chatbots will be handling 85 percent of customer-service interactions; they… 11 min read
 Adapters: A Compact and Extensible Transfer Learning Method for NLP [ read more ] Adapters obtain comparable results to BERT on several NLP tasks while achieving parameter efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Similar Quora Questions with Word2Vec and Xgboost  </title>
      <link>/posts/finding-similar-quora-questions-with-word2vec-and-xgboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/finding-similar-quora-questions-with-word2vec-and-xgboost/</guid>
      <description>--- title: &#34;Finding Similar Quora Questions with Word2Vec and Xgboost &#34; author: date: 2019-06-27 slug: categories: - similar - product - learning - week - datascience - AI tags: - similar - product - learning - week - datascience - AI isCJKLanguage: no --- Finding Similar Quora Questions with Word2Vec and Xgboost [ read more ] Last week, we explored different techniques for de-duplication for identifying similar documents using BOW… 5 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write a Simple Summarizer in Python  </title>
      <link>/posts/write-a-simple-summarizer-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/write-a-simple-summarizer-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Write a Simple Summarizer in Python [ read more ] A Gentle Introduction to Natural Language Processing 8 min read
 Why you should totally switch to Kotlin [ read more ] It’s time to start using a modern programming language 7 min read
 How to think like a programmer - lessons in problem solving [ read more ] If you’re interested in programming, you may well have seen this quote before: 7 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem Of Overfitting And How To Resolve It  </title>
      <link>/posts/the-problem-of-overfitting-and-how-to-resolve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-problem-of-overfitting-and-how-to-resolve-it/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Of Overfitting And How To Resolve It [ read more ] Explaining How To Fix The Curse Of Overfitting In Python 6 min read
 A Technical Look at How Criminals Use AI [ read more ] Machine learning is one of the most exciting new features used in technology today. However, it is… 6 min read
 The amazing power of long/short term memory networks (LSTMs) [ read more ] Long short term memory networks have both long- and short term memory, and this makes them ideal for… 3 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem Of Overfitting And How To Resolve It  </title>
      <link>/posts/the-problem-of-overfitting-and-how-to-resolve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-problem-of-overfitting-and-how-to-resolve-it/</guid>
      <description>The Problem Of Overfitting And How To Resolve It [ read more ] Explaining How To Fix The Curse Of Overfitting In Python 6 min read
 A Technical Look at How Criminals Use AI [ read more ] Machine learning is one of the most exciting new features used in technology today. However, it is… 6 min read
 The amazing power of long/short term memory networks (LSTMs) [ read more ] Long short term memory networks have both long- and short term memory, and this makes them ideal for… 3 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19 Things You Need to Learn to Become an Effective Angular Developer  </title>
      <link>/posts/19-things-you-need-to-learn-to-become-an-effective-angular-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/19-things-you-need-to-learn-to-become-an-effective-angular-developer/</guid>
      <description>19 Things You Need to Learn to Become an Effective Angular Developer [ read more ] A comprehensive guide on how to become a pro at Angular 10 min read
 An introduction to Git merge and rebase: what they are, and how to use them [ read more ] As a Developer, many of us have to choose between Merge &amp;amp; Rebase. With all the references we get from the… 6 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to StanfordNLP: An NLP Library for 53 Languages (with Python code)  </title>
      <link>/posts/introduction-to-stanfordnlp-an-nlp-library-for-53-languages-with-python-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/introduction-to-stanfordnlp-an-nlp-library-for-53-languages-with-python-code/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to StanfordNLP: An NLP Library for 53 Languages (with Python code) [ read more ] A tutorial on Stanford’s latest library - StanfordNLP. I showcase an implementation on basic NLP tasks in… 8 min read
 Web Architecture 101 [ read more ] The basic architecture concepts I wish I knew when I was getting started as a web developer 11 min read
 Natural Language Processing is Fun!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mistakes I Made As a Beginner Programmer  </title>
      <link>/posts/the-mistakes-i-made-as-a-beginner-programmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-mistakes-i-made-as-a-beginner-programmer/</guid>
      <description>The Mistakes I Made As a Beginner Programmer [ read more ] Learn to identify them, make habits to avoid them 29 min read
 How I planned my meals with Reinforcement Learning on a budget [ read more ] Following my recent article on applying Reinforcement Learning to real life problems, I decided to… 16 min read
 SOLID Principles every Developer Should Know [ read more ] A short yet detailed introduction to understanding SOLID design principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic NLP Tutorial for News Multiclass Categorization  </title>
      <link>/posts/a-basic-nlp-tutorial-for-news-multiclass-categorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-basic-nlp-tutorial-for-news-multiclass-categorization/</guid>
      <description>A Basic NLP Tutorial for News Multiclass Categorization [ read more ] Natural Language Processing, Support Vector Machine, TF- IDF, deep learning, Spacy, Attention LSTM 6 min read
 Dissecting BERT Part 1: The Encoder [ read more ] This is Part 1/2 of Understanding BERT written jointly by Miguel Romero and Francisco Ingham. If you already… 12 min read
 Machine Learning is Fun! [ read more ] The world’s easiest introduction to Machine Learning 15 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Threat of Google DeepMind</title>
      <link>/posts/the-threat-of-google-deepmind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-threat-of-google-deepmind/</guid>
      <description>The Threat of Google’s DeepMind [ read more ] If you consider Google is the leader globally in artificial intelligence, DeepMind is their crown jewel. 5 min read
 What is the next big thing in AI and ML? [ read more ] And is there one? 16 min read
 Aspect-Based Opinion Mining (NLP with Python) [ read more ] If you’ve heard of Uber or Amazon, you may be one of 40 million (Uber) or over 310 million (Amazon) active… 9 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Movie Genres using NLP  </title>
      <link>/posts/predicting-movie-genres-using-nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/predicting-movie-genres-using-nlp/</guid>
      <description>Predicting Movie Genres using NLP [ read more ] An Awesome Introduction to Multi-Label Classification 12 min read
 How to think like a programmer - lessons in problem solving [ read more ] If you’re interested in programming, you may well have seen this quote before: 7 min read
 Natural Language Processing is Fun! [ read more ] How computers understand Human Language 16 min read
 Web Architecture 101 [ read more ] The basic architecture concepts I wish I knew when I was getting started as a web developer 11 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-label Text Classification using BERT – The Mighty Transformer</title>
      <link>/posts/multi-label-text-classification-using-bert-the-mighty-transformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/multi-label-text-classification-using-bert-the-mighty-transformer/</guid>
      <description>Multi-label Text Classification using BERT – The Mighty Transformer [ read more ] The past year has ushered in an exciting age for Natural Language Processing using deep neural networks… 7 min read
 A Brief Introduction To GANs (and how to code them) [ read more ] With explanations of the math and code 5 min read
 TensorFlow is dead, long live TensorFlow! [ read more ] If you’re an AI enthusiast and you didn’t see the big news this month, you might have just snoozed through an… 8 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Tensor Processing Units</title>
      <link>/posts/understanding-tensor-processing-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/understanding-tensor-processing-units/</guid>
      <description>Understanding Tensor Processing Units [ read more ] In 2017, Google announced a Tensor Processing Unit (TPU) - a custom application-specific integrated circuit… 8 min read
 How to get started with Machine Learning in about 10 minutes [ read more ] With the rise of Machine Learning inside industries. The need of a tool that can help you iterate through the… 10 min read
 Alibaba Open-Sources Mars to Complement NumPy [ read more ] “NumPy” is a beloved tool for the huge population of Python users who are mathematicians, engineers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little-Known A.I. Method Can Train on Your Health Data Without Threatening…</title>
      <link>/posts/a-little-known-a.i.-method-can-train-on-your-health-data-without-threatening/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-little-known-a.i.-method-can-train-on-your-health-data-without-threatening/</guid>
      <description>A Little-Known A.I. Method Can Train on Your Health Data Without Threatening… [ read more ] Machine learning has great potential to transform disease diagnosis and detection, but it’s been held back by… 5 min read
 Fei-Fei Li’s Stanford Team Is Crowdsourcing Robot Training [ read more ] Sorting a bunch of differently coloured toy trucks and action figures seems like child’s play, right… 4 min read
 Explainable AI: From Prediction To Understanding [ read more ] It’s not enough to make predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signing With Alexa: A DIY Experiment in AI Accessibility</title>
      <link>/posts/signing-with-alexa-a-diy-experiment-in-ai-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/signing-with-alexa-a-diy-experiment-in-ai-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>Signing With Alexa: A DIY Experiment in AI Accessibility [ read more ] With its fluent voice interactions and ever-widening library of skills, Amazon’s virtual assistant Alexa… 4 min read
 Word2Vec - a baby step in Deep Learning but a giant leap towards Natural… [ read more ] Let’s demystify word2vec with reasoning, examples and mathematics 10 min read
 What is the next big thing in AI and ML?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sentiment analysis: Machine-Learning approach</title>
      <link>/posts/sentiment-analysis-machine-learning-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sentiment-analysis-machine-learning-approach/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment analysis: Machine-Learning approach [ read more ] Second blog post published on my Data Science project for Reputation.com 8 min read
 Artificial Intelligence - The Revolution Hasn’t Happened Yet [ read more ] Artificial Intelligence (AI) is the mantra of the current era. The phrase is intoned by technologists… 16 min read
 Unsupervised Text Summarization using Sentence Embeddings [ read more ] I will describe the approach that I used to perform Text Summarization on a multi language dataset of… 13 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Algorithms Mess Up, the Nearest Human Gets the Blame</title>
      <link>/posts/when-algorithms-mess-up-the-nearest-human-gets-the-blame/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/when-algorithms-mess-up-the-nearest-human-gets-the-blame/</guid>
      <description>When Algorithms Mess Up, the Nearest Human Gets the Blame [ read more ] A look at historical case studies shows us how we handle the liability of automated systems 5 min read
 Synchronized SGD Outdated? Yoshua Bengio on Hardware-Friendly DL [ read more ] DeepMind’s 2018 AlphaGo Zero requires 300,000 times more computing power than AlexNet did in 2013. With… 7 min read
 A Leap into the Future: Generative Adversarial Networks [ read more ] Is December 12, 2018, a day the world changed forever?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Is Why A.I. Has Yet to Reshape Most Businesses</title>
      <link>/posts/this-is-why-a.i.-has-yet-to-reshape-most-businesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/this-is-why-a.i.-has-yet-to-reshape-most-businesses/</guid>
      <description>This Is Why A.I. Has Yet to Reshape Most Businesses [ read more ] For many companies, deploying A.I. is slower and more expensive than it might seem 8 min read
 Facebook Says Developers Will Love PyTorch 1.0 [ read more ] At the first-ever PyTorch Developer Conference today in San Francisco, Facebook released a preview of PyTorch… 3 min read
 Cheat Sheets for AI, Neural Networks, Machine Learning, Deep Learning &amp;amp; Big… [ read more ] The Most Complete List of Best AI Cheat Sheets 7 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning Could Reveal Why the World Works the Way It Does</title>
      <link>/posts/deep-learning-could-reveal-why-the-world-works-the-way-it-does/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/deep-learning-could-reveal-why-the-world-works-the-way-it-does/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning Could Reveal Why the World Works the Way It Does [ read more ] At a major AI research conference, one researcher laid out how existing AI techniques might be used to… 6 min read
 Fei-Fei Li’s Stanford Team Is Crowdsourcing Robot Training [ read more ] Sorting a bunch of differently coloured toy trucks and action figures seems like child’s play, right… 4 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Way to Build Tiny Neural Networks Could Create Powerful AI on Your Phone</title>
      <link>/posts/a-new-way-to-build-tiny-neural-networks-could-create-powerful-ai-on-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-new-way-to-build-tiny-neural-networks-could-create-powerful-ai-on-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>A New Way to Build Tiny Neural Networks Could Create Powerful AI on Your Phone [ read more ] We’ve been wasting our processing power to train neural networks that are 10 times too big 6 min read
 How to classify photos in 600 classes using nine million Open Images [ read more ] If you’re looking to train an image classifier for fun or profit and are in need of data to do it, look no… 8 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>36 Amazing Python Open Source Projects (v.2019)</title>
      <link>/posts/36-amazing-python-open-source-projects-v.2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/36-amazing-python-open-source-projects-v.2019/</guid>
      <description>36 Amazing Python Open Source Projects (v.2019) [ read more ] For the past year, we’ve compared nearly 5,000 open source Python projects and selected the top 36. 6 min read
 NLP Guide: Identifying Part of Speech Tags using Conditional Random Fields [ read more ] POS tagging is the process of marking up a word in a corpus to a corresponding part of speech tag, based on… 6 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences Between AI and Machine Learning and Why it Matters</title>
      <link>/posts/differences-between-ai-and-machine-learning-and-why-it-matters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/differences-between-ai-and-machine-learning-and-why-it-matters/</guid>
      <description>Differences Between AI and Machine Learning and Why it Matters [ read more ] Unfortunately, some tech organizations are deceiving customers by proclaiming using AI on their technologies… 13 min read
 Word2Vec - a baby step in Deep Learning but a giant leap towards Natural… [ read more ] Let’s demystify word2vec with reasoning, examples and mathematics 10 min read
 Report on Text Classification using CNN, RNN &amp;amp; HAN [ read more ] Experimenting with various neural networks architectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 reasons Microsoft has become the go-to for machine learning</title>
      <link>/posts/6-reasons-microsoft-has-become-the-go-to-for-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/6-reasons-microsoft-has-become-the-go-to-for-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>6 reasons Microsoft has become the go-to for machine learning [ read more ] Including the latest tools announced at Microsoft Build 2019 7 min read
 An Overview of Human Pose Estimation with Deep Learning [ read more ] An introduction to the techniques used in Human Pose Estimation based on Deep Learning. 9 min read
 Text Preprocessing in Python: Steps, Tools, and Examples [ read more ] by Olga Davydova, Data Monsters 7 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are developers still using Angular?</title>
      <link>/posts/why-are-developers-still-using-angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/why-are-developers-still-using-angular/</guid>
      <description>Why are developers still using Angular? [ read more ] especially when everyone seems to be wanting React 4 min read
 Text Mining 101: A Stepwise Introduction to Topic Modeling using Latent… [ read more ] Have you ever been inside a well-maintained library? I’m always incredibly impressed with the way the… 10 min read
 Unsupervised Text Summarization using Sentence Embeddings [ read more ] I will describe the approach that I used to perform Text Summarization on a multi language dataset of… 13 min read</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing for Fuzzy String Matching with Python</title>
      <link>/posts/natural-language-processing-for-fuzzy-string-matching-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/natural-language-processing-for-fuzzy-string-matching-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Natural Language Processing for Fuzzy String Matching with Python [ read more ] In computer science, fuzzy string matching is the technique of finding strings that match a pattern… 5 min read
 JIT fast! Supercharge tensor processing in Python with JIT compilation [ read more ] Numba can speed up tensor processing work in Python by an order of magnitude. Read on for one of the easiest… 11 min read</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>